Can you just run down real quick just
like the last four picks what the
today's picks and what you liked about
each guy?
>> Sure. Um
can I say something first? I want to um
um thank the uh personnel staff starting
with um our general manager Adam Peters.
um our scouting staff um a lot of work
goes into into uh this process and today
especially is um you know very uh very
scout driven and very you know kind of
departmental in terms of uh it's kind of
a special day for the department with so
many things you know that we usually
have the most picks on day three we do a
lot of stuff after the draft adding to
our roster so um it's kind of a
culmination of a lot of work over the
course of the year and it kind
um comes to an end today in terms of uh
this draft, the the finality of it. And
uh a lot of people did a lot of great
work to get us to this point. And I just
want to acknowledge that and um was
doing some reflecting over the weekend
about how far we've come as a department
since getting here in terms of you know,
you know, the process, the uh the draft
room itself. You know, just uh feel like
we've made a lot of really good progress
and there's a lot of people to thank for
that. starting with our owner Josh
Harris and and um and AP's kind of been
steadfast in in his belief on how things
should be and how it should look and um
we've made a lot of great progress and I
just wanted to acknowledge that and and
and thank the people involved with that.
So, um on to your question, sorry. Um,
in terms of our players that we selected
today, we started with, uh, Joshua
Joseph in the fifth round, a guy that,
uh, you know, we had a lineman on kind
of across the department, you know,
scouts, coaches, um, R&D, you know, a
lot of, uh, belief in this kid and, and
he's a well-rounded player. He's a he's
a good player versus the run. He's a,
um, a pass rusher that is, he impacts
the game, and we feel like there's still
more to come in that part of it. The one
constant you kind of feel with him is is
his length. He's got, you know,
excellent length. You really feel his
his range with his upper body and um his
ability to to affect the passer and and
impact the run game with just how long
and and um rangy he is with his upper
body. Um you know, a guy that we're
excited about and still feel like
there's a lot more to come there um in
terms of development. Um in the sixth
round at pick 187, we took Kron Allen.
Um really cool kid um from Virginia. Um
all-time leading rusher in Penn State
history. 39 career touchdowns. You know,
a true like um you know, move the line
of scrimmage pile push uh power player.
Um a lot of uh you know, defenders
falling backwards as they're bringing
them down. Just kind of a lot of power,
dirty yards that you maybe you don't
always appreciate, but they uh they mean
a lot. Really good short yardage player.
Um and and really a cool kid. uh that
that's just been very productive for a
very long time there. Someone that we
respect and and and um just kind of
appreciate his game and it gives us
something that um is a little bit unique
to our back field. Um at pick 209 in the
sixth round, we took uh Matt Goldman
from Michigan State. Um you know, he
played center this year for Michigan
State after transferring from Wake
Forest where he had played um guard. So,
he's got some utility on the inside that
he's demonstrated on in college. Um, a
guy that uh just like the way he plays
the game. Kind of a a physical, you
know, get a find a way to get it done.
Nasty. Uh, guy that's just got like grit
and toughness to everything he does. Um,
guy that we just feel like is uh a guy
that plays the game that we want to play
it and uh guy that we respect. Another
guy that we just feel is a got commander
traits to him as a player and and what
he is as a person too. And then uh with
our uh seventh round pick, we took Aan
from Ruters. Um
>> I didn't get the last
>> uh I'll leave it to you.
Um really cool kid. Uh great energy,
man. Uh I would say the first thing that
that uh when I think of him is is
energy. Um just a guy that truly loves
the game of football, passionate about
the game of football and um really saw
uh his career really take off late in
late in his career. You know, he um you
know, statistically everything popped um
last year, completion percentage, led
the Big 10 in passing yards, um you
know, touchdown interception ratio,
everything improved. Everything um is on
the upswing with him in terms of uh
production. And uh like I said, just a
guy that brings great energy and love of
football to your building and to your to
your room. Um we had the the
interactions we had with him. Um I
thought he just felt a guy that uh
brought life life to any room he's in.
And and really all these guys we um the
interactions that we had with all all
four of those guys that I just mentioned
um were very positive with our uh with
our organization. So,
>> when you're looking at on day three and
you're going over like maybe some future
needs now or future needs, how do you
weigh that with some of what you see on
the board? Like if you know if you still
need maybe someone else in the secondary
but someone else is there, what's the
process that you go through with those?
>> I think every every pick you look at at
at where you are roster-wise now, you
look at where you are roster-wise in the
future, and you look at what your
options are on the board, you know. Um,
I don't think any pick is ever just, oh,
we really like this guy. It's always how
does he fit? How does he fit in 2026?
How does he fit beyond that? Um, what
else is out there? So, I think every
pick you kind of approach it the same
whether it's the first round or the
seventh round to be honest with you. You
just always look at how's what's his
path to making our team? What's his path
to impacting our team? Um, what are our
options? What else? What are we turning
down to take this player? So, and then
you're also always looking it does it
make sense to try to potentially move.
So, every pick I think you approach it
very very similar to be honest with you.
>> Hey Lance, considering the importance of
quarterback, how much of a priority is
it to say, hey, in any given year, if
there's somebody there where wherever
the draft, especially day three, it's
important to get that because you always
have to fortify that position.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's it's obviously
critically important like you said and
it's it's unique. I think every year you
look um to see if someone makes sense
with where you are roster-wise. You
know, obviously, you know, we are where
we are with with Jaden and and
um with Marcus and with Sam. So, this
guy at this time just made sense to we
liked a lot about him and, you know, we
wanted to always, you know, see if we
can address that position. And I think
you're always looking at that, like you
said, every year to to see if somebody
makes sense to add and and if you see
developmental qualities and how how that
might uh create competition and and you
know, make the people the the rest of
the people in the room, you know, even
better. So, um he just made sense on a
lot of levels for us. So, um we're
excited to add him.
>> And with the draft being sort of the
culmination, I know there's more to come
here. you guys could do more in free
agency, but the bigger stuff, uh, you
guys made a priority to get younger
faster throughout this whole process.
How do you kind of feel the draft help
you kind of cap that off with?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think, you know, what we
did in free agency, I I thought was
great that we did, we got younger, we
got faster, and we you're always trying
to create an opportunity for yourself in
the draft to not be like pigeon holed
into doing we have to do this, we have
to do that. And um I think Adam did a
great job of kind of setting us up to be
in that situation again where we went
into this draft, you know, very free to
to to go after, you know, athletic fast
players wherever they might be. It
wasn't we have to do this, we have to do
that. So um I think our plan was to to
have that kind of flexibility and and
that's that's what we had. So I thought
it went well.
Hey, Lance. Uh, now that the picture has
been painted a little bit more, uh,
through free agency, through the draft,
now and depth is always a key thing, how
do you all think that you fared with
adding more depth and what needs still
to be added depthwise in some of the
areas?
>> Well, I think we addressed a lot of what
we perceived as needs and and we uh I
think we created competition and we
created depth really in every room. Um,
I think we'll probably take a step back
next week and and look at where we are
roster-wise after the draft, after um
the undrafted free agency process, and
just take an assessment of of where we
are. Do we still feel um you know, we
have voids that we can address, what's
out there to potentially do that. Um,
you know, we try to leave ourselves a
little bit of flexibility to do that at
the end of the draft process to maybe
there is somebody that falls through,
maybe there is somebody that um is still
out there from um the free agency
process that might make sense. So, I
think next week we'll do kind of an
audit of exactly where we are and and
what we could potentially add to to to
make our depth even better than it is
now.
>> When you look at the players that you
drafted this year, did anybody stand
out? Did you find out anything new about
some of these guys that you did not know
going into this?
>> Oh man.
Um
I can't I can't say that I did. I I feel
like we when we go into the draft, I
feel like we really are prepared and I
feel like we really know these guys and
uh our scouts do a great job of kind of
informing us of um you know what we what
we're getting not only in players but as
people and um you know as we as we
talked through these players I felt like
um
we had great knowledge of them and
didn't really feel any surprises or any
um any new information like that
surfaced. I think we feel really good
about all these guys.
>> Hey Lance, good evening. How are you?
>> I'm so I'm good.
>> Um Josh Joseph, we saw in his um kind of
bio about his ability to force
turnovers. So when you either
>> saw him in person or looked at the film,
what were some things that really stood
out to you in terms of just how he was
able to do that? Well, like I said, I
think you feel the the the the arm
length in everything he does. And that a
lot of times in, you know, at least in
my history, I I feel like when when
someone has that kind of um upper body
range and length, that it does tend to
create turnovers. And it does, you do
feel like that impacts the ability to
create turnovers, whether it be um
tipping passes that create
interceptions, whether it be stripping
the quarterback, whether it be, you
know, pursuing down the line of
scrimmage and knocking a ball out, you
know, from the backside chase. Um I feel
like that's a huge part of that of that
one thing unlocks the next, if that
makes sense. That length just seems to
always factor in. And plus, he's a
physical, you know, heavy-handed player
that, you know, when he hits people,
they feel it. So, um, I think, you know,
the way he plays a game and that length,
you know, kind of equate to creating
turnovers.
>> A general draft evaluation question
because I know at this point in time,
folks always want to go and say, "Oh,
this team did well in the draft board
and all of that, but at what point do
you all look at how well you did in a
draft?" Like, are there particular um
evaluation periods or just an evaluation
time or is it kind of like you're always
evaluating? Yeah, I think you know you
every year you look back on on your
classes, you know, we'll next we'll look
back on this class a year from now and
see what we got from it and versus what
our expectations were. I I think we
still look back at our first class, you
know, from 24 and um assess where where
we feel like we got it right, feel like
what what could we have done better on
certain picks and decisions. I I think
you're always doing that. There's kind
of like the the industry standard is of,
you know, after year three, you kind of
assess where where everything fell. But
I I I don't really buy that. I think
you're always looking at every year,
you're looking back at each class and
and seeing uh how well you think you did
and and what maybe in retrospect you
might have, you know, want to improve or
change.
>> Hey, good evening, Lance.
>> Hey.
>> Um I know you guys go through this
process, you're more worried about what
a guy can bring to your team, not what
they can't bring to your team. But when
we talk to these players and ask them
about some of their perceived
shortcomings, so many of them believe
it's a misunderstanding or it's
underrated or they just didn't get to do
it a lot in college. Is there a part of
your process where you maybe identify
like this player supposedly can't do
this as well, but you look for clues
that maybe they can, they're just not
being asked to do it?
>> Yeah. I mean, I think we're always
trying to identify exactly what we think
we're going to be getting in terms of
the ability level. And sometimes we
we'll we'll we'll we'll we'll try to get
a feel for what their like
self-awareness is, if that makes sense,
where they feel um like how honest they
are with themselves at certain times,
you know, in terms of their their their
own self scout to some degree. Um you
know, we always try to get um a really
really focused uh
picture of what we really believe we're
going to be getting and try to see if it
matches with with with what they see
themselves as. There are times where you
where you scout a player and you're
like, man, this guy really, you know,
he's doesn't have great feel for what he
is and what his strengths are. You know,
there are some um it's like a like a big
man in basketball that shooting threes
all the time. You know, there's some
guys that just don't get what they're
good at. Um so, we try to identify guys
that really know themselves and know
exactly what they are as players and
hope usually that when that matches with
what we feel that we feel good about
that, you know, does that make sense?
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay.
>> Absolutely. I appreciate it. Um, before
the draft, you kind of talked about how
you do pay attention to some of the
mocks and some of like the national big
boards to kind of just get a vibe of
what the public uh things might happen.
Now that we're done with it, uh, the
public perception appears to be you guys
got really good value across your board.
I think you're like top three or four in
the value measurements. How much does
that kind of I know obviously internal
confidence is important, but how much
does that play into your evaluation of
how confident you are in your process?
I mean, I think it's always good to to
hear that or to to see that, you know,
that um that, you know, people outside
this building think we're getting great
value. I think when we make our
decisions,
we have that in mind, but we want to
really maximize these picks and get
great value for them, especially this
year when we were a little bit down in
numbers in terms of uh pick volume. So,
um I think it was really important that
we approached each pick with a very, you
know, u measured, you know, strategic
approach in terms of, hey, we got to
make sure that, you know, we get great
value here. We got to make sure that we
have, um, you know, kind of
organizational buyin in terms of the,
you know, scouts, coaches, um, R&D that
we're aligned and we feel good about
these picks. And um yeah, I I I think
you're always trying to get great value
and you're always trying to pick the
right the right player for the right
situation. And um feel like we've done a
pretty good job with that and and we
always every pick we we tried to do
that.
>> How do you guys
there instead of them? How did you
address those positions and then what
was left on the board compared to what
you got?
>> Well, I mean, I think we feel good about
those rooms. You know, we we feel like
we have um good players in there. We
have good competition in there. And it
wasn't a situation where we went into
the draft to not address them. It just
the way that I think you go into the
draft like like we talked about earlier
with great flexibility to do whatever is
best. And it just was a situation where
where we were picking and what was
available, those rooms just didn't make
sense at that at that time. So, it
wasn't that it was not considered. It
wasn't that um you know, it everything's
fine. It's just it was that
when we were picking a player in those
rooms just didn't make the sense as the
best decision at that point. So, um like
I said, we feel good about those rooms.
I think we're always wanting to have
competition and and always wanting to um
do everything we can to make make our
football team as good as it can be, but
at those picks, those rooms just didn't
click.
>> Anything else? Anybody in the back?
>> Thanks, Lance.
>> All right, guys. Thank you.
>> Have a great weekend.